[Music]
foreign
automation tutorial
so in my previous lesson
we started
automating the test case
and I have explained you the step one
where we'll be creating the where we
created the test case folder structure
so this is our lesson 9 where I'm gonna
cover this step two to create the steps
using the modules that we created
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive notification
whenever I publish more videos thank you
okay so our agenda item is create test
tips
so we need to populate your test case
with the test steps so in the previous
session we created test case folder
structure right now
we need to populate the test steps
so how we can do that I am going to
teach you in this session
and we are going to use this standard
subset that is dot TSU file provided by
present testoster with your task
installation so I have already explained
you how to install Tasker in my first
session okay go through that session
okay and while using these standard
modules to perform common steering
operations and our own created modules
by using xcan that means we need to use
the standard modules and also the
modules that we created to create the
test tips
okay and then there are two ways to
create the test steps in Tosca
first way is either you can drag and
drop the module onto your test case or
test case folder
and the second method is you can use the
function called ADD test tip at test
case or test case folder level
okay so now let's jump onto the system
and see how can we create test steps by
using Tasker okay so this is my Tasker
16 okay so in my previous session I have
already showed you where we created test
case structure okay so in this session
now we are going to create test steps
for your test case structure folder okay
so in my previous session we have
created this entire folder
let me copy this folder
copy and then paste this folder here
and rename this folder
as
session
0 9
test
steps
creation
okay
so once you rename
just minimize the previous folder and
expand this folder
so before I create test steps I just
want to show you
module creation okay so I have already
showed you how to create module but
for this session we are gonna create a
basic module so that you'll be able to
understand how to create your modules to
capture the controls your viewer system
under test okay so as you all know my
system under test is demo webshop
trycentage.com Okay so
I'm gonna create
a small module where I'm gonna capture
all the controls that are required to
log it
My Demo webshop okay so let me create
quickly
go to modules section
go to webshop
I've already created a small folder
called customer okay and this is my
subfolder so I'm gonna capture all the
controls in this particular folder
how to scan your system under test by
right clicking on the module
click on scan and click on application
so as soon as you click on application
it opens all the applications
that are open your system in your system
so this is the application that I would
like to
x-scan demo webshop
and click on scan
so now
I would like to
go back to my basic view so I have
already explained you about this xscan
all the options that are available in
xscan and how to perform x-scan in my
previous sessions okay I would recommend
you guys to go through that particular
session
so I would like to shift to my basic
View
and then I would like to capture all the
elements that are actually required for
login okay
I'm gonna capture email click on this
password
remember me
forgot password
login button
okay I captured all of them
okay and then let's go to Advanced View
and
select this top filter
you decrease the filter so that you can
see only selected controls so you just
need to
drag to the left so that you can see
only the controls that are
selected
and make sure that the naming Convention
of your controls are proper so I can see
everything is correct
and rename this module
as
demo
webshop
demo webshop okay demo
webshop demo webshop
log in
login page okay and once you rename this
module also make sure that that make
sure that the title of this page is
parameterized I mean uh you you need to
use regular expression as I explained
you earlier this webshop
right this URL the title of the page
keeps on changing based on the page
where you are okay so now I would like
to
use the regular expression so that this
title works for all the pages what I'm
doing I'm keeping star after demo
webshop
Okay click ok
and now
save the module
and then close your x-can
and now
just go back to your module section and
see the demo webshop login
right so I have captured all the
controls that are required for login
okay in the same way I have already
captured
all the controls for different modules
like
apparents and shoe product and what is
my product Choice tab right what product
Choice tab is product categories like
these actually all these product
categories and these product categories
a person choose once I go to
appearance and shoes blue jeans right I
have captured all the controls
in different modules okay these are all
the webshop modules they are that I have
already captured in the same manner how
we captured login page okay
so now let's go back to test cases
so now we need to populate
test steps
under the test case structure folders
right so first let's go to precondition
let's populate the steps under
precondition so to populate the steps
you need to keep your modules aside so
drag and drop to the right I've already
showed you all these options okay
and now your test case
is
here your test case
okay once again
you can see the test case here
correct
left side and your modules right side
okay
and now
let me just drag and drop okay let's
adjust this
adjust this okay
so for a login
I have already create sorry for
precondition what is my precondition
I have to first
enter the demo webshop URL correct so
let's go to
demo webshop URL so if you see under
webshop oh sorry under standard modules
under t-box engine
under HTML I've already showed you so
these standard modules are
created by Tosca so that you can use
these standard modules for any kind of
application okay
so under this I have a module I have a
module called open URL drag this
and drop here
so the open URL I dragged and dropped
here okay
I'm not gonna populate any values for
the test tips so we are going to
populate the values in the next session
for this session we are gonna
create
test steps for the test case structure
okay
so now next
we dragged and dropped and let me also
create post condition where I'm gonna
close the browser right just drag this
module and drop into post condition
that's it close the browser
now let's go to precondition again
and once you open
your
web browser what we need to do I need to
navigate to login page from where see
this is my top menu right
click on login
so that means
I have to click on login for that
I have another module
so one more thing is either you can drag
and drop from this way or let me just
put the module back to the tabs and now
there is another way under precondition
I need to click on login right for this
instead of dragging and dropping there
is another way you can right click on
this precondition
and
search and add step
okay this searches your modules what are
the modules we saw here it shows here
also or just click on Ctrl t
Ctrl plus t Okay so that also opens your
modules okay so now navigate to login
page right so for that I need a module
called top menu so where I have stored
all the controls of your top menu okay
I've already created that let me just
search on top menu
so web shop top menu
select this
as soon as you select
that step is created
under this top menu I'm going to click
on login how you need to enter the
values to perform or to steer the
application that I am going to explain
in the next session so we are going to
just add the test steps
but later we are gonna
we are gonna populate the values okay
and then once I click on login I need to
oh sorry once I
one say
select login correct once I select login
now my next step is
to basically
I need to login page okay so I need a
login page so just now we created a
login page module right so let's go to
precondition let's go to precondition so
precondition is login opening URL
clicking on login and then provide your
credentials right so again place your
cursor here Ctrl t
just now we create a login if you see
demo webshop login page this is what the
module we created just now
that's it
done once I log in now your process
starts so let's now go to your process
first you will be ordering your product
how
from the product Choice table
right from the product chart let me log
in okay here let me log in here
okay
oh sorry
so once you log in
from the product choice this is product
choice I already created a module called
Product
Choice Tab and I stored all these
controls all these links in that product
Choice tab okay
I'm gonna click on this appearance issue
so that means I need to
add a module called Product Choice tab
go here under process what is my first
order product
go to order product here again place
right click
search at the step product
product
Choice product Choice tab if you see
here this is my module add this module
okay
and you can select the category product
category from here actually which one
apparents issue but we are not gonna
populate the values in this session okay
once that is done under order product
again
under order product now once I click on
this application Shoe Right
I need to select the blue jeans correct
so let's right click
so basically we have to rename all these
actually let me rename this okay see
this
webshop product Choice tab right better
Union in this so that it will be
meaningful you will understand what you
are performing here okay here
navigate to
apparels
and
shoes
so this module uh this test step is to
navigate to operation shoes correct and
then
now you need to go to Blue Jeans you
need to go to Blue Jeans navigate to
Blue Jeans how and I have already added
a module called Ctrl t
apparels and shoes if you see here
apparels and choose product selection
Okay click on this
and rename this
as
navigate to
blue jeans okay
so once that is done you need to order
blue jeans right so for ordering the
blue jeans I have
a module called Blue Jeans
see this is the module
and rename this as
order
blue jeans
okay that is done
so this session will be a bit long a bit
longer because we are going to complete
entire end-to-end test case
automation right step two of your
automation okay once I order the blue
jeans
Now what is my next
task my next task is start checkout so
once I order blue jeans
I need to start the checkout process
correct
order
now you need to start the checkout
process so go to start checkout
under Start checkout
you need to
click on shopping cart that means you
need to navigate to Star shopping cart
again
you need to call the top menu here right
if you remember we already used the top
menu earlier also okay so now
Ctrl t
top menu
add this
done so once that is done
and again you will be
clicking on basically you'll be
navigating to so now let me just rename
this as
navigate
navigate to
shopping cart okay by using this module
you'll be navigating to shopping cart
and then you need to
start your shopping cart procedures
right start shopping cart procedures
okay
Ctrl t
you already have
shopping cart module if you see shopping
cart module okay just select that
and rename this as
shopping
cart procedures
shopping cart procedures so where I'm
gonna go to shopping cart
here I'll be
I'm starting the shopping cart procedure
which is
this check this box and check out okay
so once that is done shocking shopping
cart procedures and now you need to
foreign
address
shipping address shipping method payment
methods so if you go here check out you
need to now do billing address shipping
address
shipping method payment method and not
product confirmation so now that is
comes under
checkout process okay
here go to checkout process
here I already added building all the
controls related to billing I already
added as a billing address okay Ctrl t
billing so if you see billing address
that is done and then under checkout
process once you've done billing address
let me rename this as billing address
continue
sorry
billing
address
continue
and then
shipping address
again Ctrl t
I have already having a shipping address
module sorry shipping address this one
not shipping method shipping address
right and rename this as
shipping
address
continue
okay that is done and then
once you're done with your shipping
address what is next procedure you are
shipping method ground okay I will be
selecting ground okay see continue
and then shipping address
sorry
and then shipping method where I'm gonna
select ground right so again Ctrl t
shipping method
right once shipping method is done so
here what is the shipping method ground
rename this
shipping
method
ground
one shipping method is entered
you will be entering your payment method
so I'm gonna select the payment method
as credit card
okay so the for that control T I already
created
payment method
module where I captured all the controls
payment methods okay
so let's rename this
payment
method
credit card I am going to select credit
card
okay once that is done and then you will
be providing your payment information
for the credit card right for that again
Ctrl T here I need to use payment
information module payment information
module
if you see this is my payment
information credit card
so now here let me rename this as
payment information credit card
okay I'm just
renaming this payment information credit
card okay I'm just expanding
so once that is done
under checkout process you need to I
think that is it
once you provide the payment information
click on continue sorry this is your
payment information
right and then confirmation order that
means
I'm gonna
shift to verification of prices
okay so verification of prices under
verification of prices
for now so let me just
right click
so verification of prices under
verification okay
right sorry
right click a verification of prices I'm
gonna leave empty for now because I'm
gonna cover this verification of prices
in future sessions okay where we will be
validating all the prices okay for now I
just I'm gonna ignore this for now okay
here
confirmation order if you go to
confirmation
here I already have
confirmation order confirm order
and I'm going to confirm the order here
okay how clicking on confirm so that it
the order gets confirmed okay
and then
once you click on
confirm order what is our next procedure
verification of success
so under verification of success
verification of success you need to add
order successful okay
Ctrl t
order successful so that means
once you click on confirm the order
successful will come okay all the
controls related to that successful page
I stored in this module okay so once
that is done
now what is the next next one oh let me
rename this okay let me rename this
saying that
confirm okay verification of success
right verify
verify
the order
success so let also rename this one also
the previous one I think we forgot to
rename this Ctrl a what we are doing
confirm the order
we are going to click on confirm button
right
once the verification of success is done
what is our next step next step is post
condition under post condition we
already add a closed browser but here
I'm not going to close the browser I'm
going to click on continue first
correct so for that I need to add
another module called order successful
let's call this order successful again
Ctrl t
order
successful where I captured all these
see I'm gonna click on continue
so this one you need to rearrange the
order
before I close I'm going to click on
continue that's why drag and drop to the
top
once I click on continue I need to log
out correct so for that again top menu
what we are going to do we are going to
call the top menu
Ctrl t
top menu
drag this and drop here so here I'm
gonna log out click on logout
and then close your browser
correct
so that's what
we are gonna do
correct and then
log out
close your browser
so now if you see let's go to the test
steps that we have populated here how
you can see right if you want to expand
you need to expand right click and
expand all
okay
okay right click and expand all
so
it's going to expand all your test tips
right
so we populated
test steps if you see open URL
and then
here rename this also actually let me
rename this
navigate
to login page okay open URL navigate to
login page
and login once again
login with credentials
you're gonna log in with credentials
and then navigate to operant shoes and
then navigate to Blue Jeans
order the blue jeans
and then you are going to navigate to
your
shopping cart
and you're gonna start the shopping cart
procedures you're going to enter billing
address and click on continue shipping
address click on continue payment method
credit card payment information right so
now your steps are in sequence
right all your steps are sequence
so we are almost near to complete our
test case automation
so once you enter all your test steps
once you create all your test steps by
using modules
the next step is to populate the values
for each test step
that is required that's it so once you
populate the values
your test case automation is done
okay so in my next session I'm gonna
teach you how can we populate the test
case values in your test steps and then
there are some configurations that we
are going to perform test configurations
okay
and we'll be completing our test case
end-to-end automation
okay so if you have any queries leave
your comments in the comment box I'll
try to respond to your queries
it's really very very important sessions
Guys these three sessions my previous
session
today's session and my next session so
these three sessions talks about
automating your end-to-end use Case by
using task or latest version okay stay
tuned hope you all understand the
concept of creation of the test steps
for your test cases okay so in the
upcoming session we are gonna complete
test case automation
fully okay please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos thank you